

SKILLS

- RESTful API
- Webservices, Microservices and SOAP
- Frameworks: Ionic, Angular, Vue.js, Basic React, .Net Core, C#
- Languages: C, C++, C#, Java, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, Pseudocode
- Databases: MySQL, SQL Server, OracleDB, Firebase
- Technologies: Git, IBM API Connect, Xampp, Bootstrap
- Methodologies: Agile, SCRUM, Waterfall
- Data Science: Bussiness Analitics, Stadistics,
 Machine Learning, Productivization, Tableau

EDUCATION

- Computer Systems Engineer National Technological Institute of Mexico Culiacán Campus (2019-2023)
- Technical Career in Programming CBTis 224 (2016-2019)

LANGUAGES

• Spanish: Native

• English: C1/C2 Level

Portuguese: A1/A2 Level

CONTACT



+52 667 389-2461



theionicdiamond82@gmail.com uriartejesuseduardo@gmail.com



Jesús Eduardo Uriarte Avelar



ThelonicDiamond82



Thelonic Portafolio

Jesús Eduardo Uriarte Avelar

COMPUTER SYSTEMS ENGINEER

PROFILE

Passionate professional with more than 5 years of experience, with a comprehensive approach to fullstack development and solid systems training. Specialized in the creation of innovative solutions in computer engineering, standing out for my ability to work as a team and under pressure. I distinguish myself by my self-taught nature, always seeking to improve myself both professionally and personally. I constantly look for new challenges and opportunities to apply my creativity and knowledge at the forefront of technological innovation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SD Analyst - HT - DEVELO

NEORIS

2024 - Present

Consulting and analysis of development requests, development of the requested software and creation of APIs in API Connect IBM and other technologies, providing quality solutions to the client.

FullStack Developer - Trainee

NEORIS

2022 - 2024

Web development, ETL's, documented software, API's with management of microservices in order to optimize processes and provide solutions to the client.

Programming Assistant

Valdez Baluarte 2019

Temporary assistant for the development of an application in charge of monitoring delivery trucks, improving customer satisfaction.

Programming technician

Castañeda & Asociados Bienes Raíces 2019 -2020

Development and administration of landing pages, marketing management in social media publications and creation of advertising multimedia content, improving customer traffic.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Cisco® CCNA Routing and Switching: Introduction to Networks
- UNIR Diploma in Soft Skills and Managerial Skills COURSES
- -DS4B Your First Week as Data Scientist
- -Python programming course